A Guide to the Papers of Alyn W. Hess 1974-1981
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Alyn W. Hess 1974-1981
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10187-l
ca. 195 items
The collection consists of Libertarian party correspondence, minutes, party papers, printed material, and photographs collected by Alyn Hess.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Libertarian Party papers were given to the Library by Alyn Hess of Milwaukee, Wisconsin on 1982 May 10.
Scope and Content Information
The Alyn Hess papers consist of ca. 195 items, 1974-1981, correspondence, minutes, party papers, printed material, and photographs as well as notes and papers of Alyn Hess concerning the Libertarian Party at state and national levels. There is material relating to the Presidential campaigns of Ed Clark and Roger MacBride, the Wisconsin and Milwaukee Libertarian Parties, and Libertarian interest groups, including Libertarians for Gay Rights and the Association of Libertarian Feminists. Drafts of Hess' letters explaining his libertarian membership are included. This material was collected by Alyn Hess, an active member of the Wisconsin Gay Peoples Union.
Organization
The material is arranged in three sections: topical, printed, and photographs. The folders in the first section are arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Topical Material
  - Campaign: Ed Clark for President 1979-1980
  - Campaign: Roger MacBride for President 1976
  - Libertarian Interest Groups 1976-1977
  - Libertarian Party: Memoranda and Circular Letters 1977, 1980-1981
  - Libertarian Party: Notes and Papers of Alyn Hess 1975-1977, n.d.
  - Libertarian Party State Convention 1974-1977
  - Milwaukee Libertarian Party: Minutes 1975-1976
  - Wisconsin Libertarian Party and Affiliates 1975-1980, n.d.
- Printed Material
  - Printed Material re the Libertarian Party 1976-1977
- Photographic Material
  - Photographs of Wisconsin Libertarian Party during the Roger MacBride Campaign 1976